Arduino: The Documentary
Arduino started as a project that we did at the Interaction Design Institute Ivrea, back in 2005.
But it has some roots in previous projects that we worked on
because we wanted to make a tool for our students that was more modern than what was available
on the market at the moment especially because the tool that everybody was using
this called the BASIC Stamp, in Italy was costing at the time about 76 Euros, that's like $100,
so it was very expensive for the students, they wouldn't do any ... too much work,
because they didn't want to spend money on buying many boards that expensive.
So what happened we started to look at possible alternatives
and also we were, working on Processing, the Processing language,
because Casey Reas, one of the founders, was one of the teachers in Ivrea,
so we thought "Why don't we try to figure out how to make Processing for the hardware?"
So we worked with a students who did a thesis, on the topic, and that produced the Wiring platform.
Hernando Barragán, a Colombian student, worked on it. And then after Hernando made Wiring, we started
to figure out how could we make the whole, platform even simpler, even cheaper, even easier to use.
And then we started to essentially reimplement the whole thing as an open source project.
We wanted it to be open source so that everybody could come and help and contribute.
Then we had another issue, that there were a lot of discussions about the school closing,
so we decided "ok, let's try to make this platform and open it up as much as possible."
David Cuartielles (Arduino Team)
Then we stopped talking about what we would like to have
and started talking about how to do it.
And when we started talking about how to do it,
Massimo had been experimenting with some technology,
I had been experimenting with a different technology.
we had a talk to decide what was best and
I decided to try this technology Massimo had,
because of its better compatibility
with different operating systems.
I checked the hardware, found a couple of bug, we fixed that,
and well, we started making boards ...
I mean, the process from starting to seriously
work on it to having a board was a mere two-days.
All the rest was software.
While I was kind of in the middle of this I met with
David Cuartielles,
who started to sort of help me
in the project, then became a major contributor
and then together we kind of made the first
Arduino hardware;
then we had David Mellis
joining as a student to write the software,
then Tom came in as an advisor,
and finally then Gianluca came in
as the person who was able to manufacture
the board itself,
that's how the team
kind of formed, by adding people by their skills.
(David Mellis, Arduino Team)
We've been using Wiring boards and wanted
to port a bunch of programs
to a cheaper microprocessor, basically, to install in some
installations,
and I helped write like
a little compatibility layer,
so that all
the old programs could run in the new
processor ...
And then just being in Ivrea and not wanting
to spend too much time on my actual thesis
I spent more and more time like working
with Massimo and the other guys developing
Arduino.
(Tom Igoe, Arduino Team)
I knew that there was this development of
hardware equivalent to Processing.
And I went over to Ivrea in June of 2005 to do a
workshop with them on another subject
and they showed me the Arduino board
at that point. And I looked at it and I said:
"You know, this is great, and it definitely works for your school,
works for my school too, but I think it
could be a larger thing,
and I think more people would want to use this."
And Massimo said: "Well, that's good feedback, thanks."
And then I went back to the States, and a couple of weeks later they wrote me and said:
"You know, we want to go further with this,
and we want to try and get it to the larger world.
"Do you want to join us as a part of the team?"
And I said "Yeah".
And it was just ... for me it was a case that this is a tool I could see using myself,
and therefore I could believe in actually helping to get it out to a wider world.
(Gianluca Martino)
After the first prototyping there was the need,
or the desire, to start manufacturing something in a more professional way,
and in a more commercial way, because all the first sample was mounted,
was done just to make them ... to let them work. After Massimo and David decided and understood
the prototype was working they needed to make a bigger batch.
So we decided to work on 200 units and we made ...
I made a little redesign, a little design for manufacturing in order to produce them.
Я внес небольшие изменения в проект, получился небольшой проект готовый для производства.
It was a test. They agreed with their school, the Interaction Design Institute, and the K3 of Malmö,
Это была проба. Они согласовали со своей школой - Interaction Design Institute и K3 из Malmö,
to buy 50 each. That was a good starting point:
that means we will not lose all the money
покупку 50 штук каждой. Это получилась хорошой отправной точкой:
т.е. это означало, что мы не потеряем всех денег
but at least half was coming back. The selling
price was exactly what we paid for
но как минимум вернем половину. Розничная цена
была точь в точь равна нашим затратам.
I think we earned 1 euro for each board, that is nothing
considering all the effort we put inside.
Я думаю мы заработали по 1 евро с платы, что ничтожно мало
по сравнению с усилиями которые мы приложили.
But after some advertisement, after some speaking
with friends, this movement started to move.
Но после небольшой рекламы, после общения с друзьями,
движению был дан старт.
And so we received the first call, our first customer, asking for one board. It was a friend of Massimo's and David's,
И мы получили первый звонок, наш первый клиент, заказал одну плату. Это был други Массимо и Давида,
but this was the beggining of something.
но это былло начало чего-то.
(Nathan Seidle, sparkfun.com)
(Натан Сейдл(?), sparkfun.com)
A few months after meeting he said "Hey Nate, Spark Fun, you guys should carry this thing called Arduino."
Через несколько месяцев после встречи он сказал "Эй  Нэт,  Spark Fun, парни вы должны распространять эту штуку называемую Arduino."
and I looked at it and at that time it was the through hole version, the RS-232 version,
и я посмотрел на на нее и в то время это была версия на выводных компонентах, с RS-232,
and I said "This looks very interesting" but I didn't really understand it.
и я сказал "Выглядит интересно" но я на самом деле не совсем понял.
And ... I hadn't wrapped my head around it. And so I said: "You know, Tom, I don't think it's for us,
И... Я отнёсся не слишком вдумчиво и сказал "Знаешь Том, я не думаю что это нам подходит,
we don't really do kits, we are not sure how people are going to react to this, and so I decided against it.
мы на самом деле не делаем наборов, т.к. не уверены как люди к ним отнесутся, и потому я принял негативное решение.
It was a few months later, six, seven months later, that Arduino came out with the full USB version,
Это было спустя несколько месяцев, шесть или семь, та Arduino вышла в полноценной USB версии,
fully assembled and tested and ready to go, and Tom again came to us
полностью собранная, протестированная, фактически - готовый продукт, и Том снова пришел к нам
and said "Hey, SparkFun, you should really carry this." And I said: "OK, well, I'm not really sure,
и сказал "Эй, SparkFun, серьезно, вы должны это распространять." И я ответил, типа:" Ок, ладно, я не очень уверен, знашь,
you know, we'll bring in 20 and see how they sell." And that was the first 20 out of about 40,000 at this point.
мы возьмем пока 20 штук и посмотрим как они будут продаваться." И это была первая двадцатка из 40 тысяч проданных на данный момент.
(Marcos García, Medialab Prado)
The first time we heard about Arduino was when David Cuartielles came to an activity
Первый раз мы услышали про Arduino когда David Cuartielles пришел на движение
called "Thursdays at Medialab", which actually was the first session of that still on-going activity.
под названеим "Четверги в Медиалаборатории", которое по сути было первым мероприятием этой серии, которая кстати продолжает проводится до сих пор.
(Gustavo Valera, Laboral)
So he keeps talking about stuff and at the end, after 90 minutes of listening to all of David's tales,
Вобщем мы общались про всякие штуки (на всякие темы), и после 90 минут выслушивания всех Девидовых историй,
he says he's involved in this project, but it was a really small thing, you know?
он сказал, что учавствует в проекте, но это типа мелочи, знаете.
And I thought "At last! Come on, David, why wasn't this the first thing you said?"
И я подумал " Наконец-то! Давай Дэвид, почему ты сразу не сказалоб этом?"
I want to talk to you about Arduino. Arduino is the last project, I finished it last week.
Я хочу поговорить про Arduino. Arduino это последний проект, я закончил его на той неделе
I talk to Ivrea's technical director and told him: "Wouldn't it be great to do something we can offer for free?"
Я общался с техническим директором Ivrea и сказал ему: "Не правда ли, было бы круто сделать что-нибудь, что мы могли бы предложить за так?"
- For free?
- Yeah
- За так?
- Ну да...
And after that, well, we worked with Gustavo, and also kept in touch with David,
И после того, мы работали с Густаво, при этом сохраняя связь с Дэвидом.
and we organized an Arduino workshop in Octover 2005, which was one of the first Arduino workshops,
и организовали Arduino воркшоп в октябре 2005, который был одним из первых воркшопов по Arduino,
if not the first one ever.
если вообще не первым.
On the last day David proposed creating some small prototypes.
В последний день Дэвид предложил сделать нескоько маленьких прототипов.
He called it "Bring your old junk and let's do something with it."
Он назвал их "Принеси свой старый мусор и наваяй что-нибудь из него."
That led to some quite interesting projects, and these people kept on doing small electronic instruments, small robots ...
Это впоследствии стало началом нескольким очень интересным проектам, и те люди продолжили дальше делать маленькие електроные инструменты, маленьких роботов...
(Phil Torrone, AdaFruit.com)
Let's see, at the time I was a senior editor at MAKE. MAKE was only a couple of years old,
Вобщем так, во времена когда я был главным редактором в журнале MAKE, ему тогда было всего пару лет,
and I had heard about this Arduino project, and I saw it online and I said:
и я услышал об проекте Arduino, и увидел его онлайн то сказал:
"Well, a lot of people are starting to talk about his, and I should check it out."
"Ну ладно, многие о нем расказывают и надо бы и мне пощупать его."
And I got one of the boards and said "Whoa, this is fantastic, begginers are gonna love this.
Вобщем заполучил я одну из платок и сказал "Ого, да это фантастика, любителям это прийдется по вкусу.
It runs on Mac, it runs on PC, it runs on Linux ... this is exactly what everyone wants."
Софт работает на Маке, на персоналках, и на Линуксе работает... это как раз то, что все хотят."
At the time a lot of people were using BASIC Stamps, they were using all sorts of microcontrollers,
В то время многие люди пользовались BASIC Stamp-ами, и вообще всем подряд.
and I come from using design tools like Flash and Processing, and I'm like
а я пришел поле использования иструментов вроде Flash и Processing, и мне понравилось
"Oh, this is perfect, it's exactly what I think everyone is going to want".
"О! Да это прекрасно... Это как раз то, чего я думаю все хотят".
And this was the beggining of when MAKE was starting to have a store, and so it took a little while,
И это было в то время когда у MAKE только появился магазин, и потому это заняло некоторое врремя,
and you know, it's very hard to do international money transfers.
и еще, эта довольно трудная штука - международные денежные переводы.
Basically we started selling Arduinos in MAKE right away, and then late on, when I started working with Limor,
Фактически мы в MAKE начали продавать Arduino как раз тогда, и потом когда я начал работать с Limor,
who's part of Adafruit, she's a founder, we also said right away:
которая из Adafruit (она основатель), мы тоже сразу сказали:
"This is a fantastic tool for getting people doing the things that they want to do with electronics."
Это фантастический инструмент для того чтоб люди делали штуки которые им хочется делать с электроникой
Not necessarily learning everything first, but getting the application done, like
Не так, чтоб сперва все выучить, а так, чтоб сразу делать приложения
I want something ... I want my dress to blink. Very hard to do if you just want to learn electronics
Я хочу чего-то... Например, хочу чтоб моя одежда мигало огоньками. Такое трудновато сделать, если вы только хотите начать изучать электронику
with an Arduino you get that done in a few minutes.
с Arduino вы можете сделать это в считанные минуты.